Guide to the Japanese-American Relocation Centers records, 1935-1953.
Japanese-American Relocation Centers records,
- Series I. Poston
  - Social welfare
    - Social Welfare Department- meetings- community services division, social welfare office (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Social Welfare Department- general cases, notes, misc. correspondence with the Welfare Office (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Juvenile Delinquency- notes (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Unmarried mothers- notes (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Moral problems- (prostitution, gambling, theft, zootsuiters)- notes and letters (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Mixed Marriages- survey forms of cases in Poston (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Mixed Marriages- release requests under mixed marriage policy (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Transfers- correspondence, requests for indefinite leave- Oct. 1942-Feb. 1943 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Internment- cases, statistics, notes from Internment Camps (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Repatriation- lists of people requesting repatriation (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Family- outline for report, meetings on family, family studies (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Family- charts and graphs for studies on: "Family and community Effort" "Family groupings" "Residence and Employment" (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Family- notes for studies and surveys, outlines for studies, general notes on families and block life (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Religion
    - Buddhists- sermons and tractates (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Buddhism- interviews and observations (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Buddhism- reports and minutes (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Buddhism- reports and minutes (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Buddhism- reports and minutes (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Buddhism- literature, service programs and assorted items (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Buddhism- literature, service programs and assorted items (in envelope) (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Buddhism- literature, service programs and assorted items (in envelope) (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Catholics- meetings and reports (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Protestants- reports on organization, charts, general overview June-Dec. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Protestants- reports on organization, charts, general overview June-Dec. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Protestants- sentiments and interviews (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Protestants- church service programs (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Protestants- church service programs (in envelope) (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Protestants- church literature and booklets (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Protestants- church literature and booklets (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Protestants- church literature and booklets (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Protestants- church literature and booklets (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Protestants- listing of religious newspapers (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Seventh Day Adventists- meetings and reports (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Evacuation, evacuee property
    - Evacuation- miscellaneous reports: attitudes toward Japanese and evacuation, WRA "Relocation Communities for Wartime Evacuees"' cause of Evacuation, causes of unrest at relocation camps, Japanese-Canadian Labor Camps (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Evacuation- miscellaneous notes, interviews, newsclippings, notes on Orange County, California, Bibliography of Japanese in California (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Evacuation- personal accounts (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Evacuation- report- The Japanese-American Youth in San Francisco 1941 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Evacuation- report- As They Await Evacuation- 1942 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Evacuation- CTS's summary and analyses, notes on every aspect of evacuation, adjustment to camp life, events in camp (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Orientation- WRA reports on Japanese culture/people, speeches on camp policies, departments, administrative orientation meetings (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Resettlement- statistics (#'s released/on leave), notes, meetings and speeches on policies, interviews (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Evacuee Property- note, correspondence about recovery, maintenance and disposition (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Segregation (to Tule Lake, California)
    - WRA report on "The Segregation Program" Notes from WRA Segregation Conference July 1943, BSR report (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Releases on segregation Aug. 10-Sept. 30, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Selective Service
    - Selective Service- general information, statistics, information about meetings, charts (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Selective Service- reaction to registration- interviews, sentiments, news clippings (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Outgroup relations
    - Outgroup- general notes, observations, conversations, newspaper circulation figures Mar.-June 1943 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Outgroup- Government policies, camp laws (voting, Earl Warren letter, notary), Cooier Speech, notes about policies, petition for "American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born" (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Outgroup- Race prejudice in Phoenix- notes, observations, talk by EHS (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Outgroup Relations- reports/study outlines- "Influences of Other Relocation Centers and Assembly Centers" Feb. 10, 1943, "No Man Argued into Slavery" Oct. 23, 1942, "Outgroup Relation" Feb. 22, 1943, "Immigrants and Citizens of Japanese Origin" Sept. 1942 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Outgroup Relations- sentiments/attitudes of outside toward camp and evacuees, letters from evacuees outside, actions of evacuees on outside (notes) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Outgroup relations- article "The Japanese-American looks at Resettlement" notes and drafts 1944 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Other Camps- Minidoka, Idaho- notes on activities, conversations, report on an unorganized relocation center Mar.-May 1943 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Other Camps- Minidoka- reports Oct. 7, 1942-Mar. 16, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Other Camps- Minidoka "Organizing a system of self-government", meetings (organization committee), lists of reps., charter (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Other camps- Manzanar, California- WRA report and description, notes/excerpts from letters, WRA report on Manzanar disturbance. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Other Camps- Tule Lake- description, WRA report "Prevalent Fears in the Tule Lake Community" (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Other Camps- Heart Mountain, Wyoming- post card, notes on an experiment in political representation by work groups at Heart Mt., excerpts from a letter, report "Colonists in Wyoming" (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Other Camps- Topaz, Utah- excerpts from letters, observations, camp diagrams (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Other Camps- Gila, Arizona- "A year at Gila" Anniversary booklet July 20, 1943, excerpts from letters (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Other Camps- Rohwer, Arkansas- excerpts from letters (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Other Camps- Jerome, Arkansas- report "Problems of the Evacuees", camp diagrams, excerpts from letters, Jenson, Arkansas- Jenson High School Graduation program (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Other Camps- Jerome, Arkansas- Community Analysis Section field reports May-Sept. 1943 topics include: Employment, education, human ecology, social relationships, repatriation, evacuee leaders, segregation, resettlement, comparison with Rohwer, administration, daily activities, co-op, effects of center life. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Other Camps- Jerome, Arkansas- other community analysis reports May-Oct. 1943 topics include: recommendations, the fence, religion, segregation reports July-Sept. 1943, monthly reports (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Other Camps- Assembly Centers (Santa Anita, Fresno) Santa Anita "Pacemaker", report on the riot at Santa Anita Sept. 3, 1942, letter on Fresno (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Congressional Relations- Dies Committee- hearings (notes), notes on reactions to committee and to hearings, methods used by committee, staff meeting on Dies- June 12, 1943, Leighton's report on Dies to Collier, Spicer's observations of Dies. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Congressional Relations- Dies Committee- W.H. Townsend's testimony- Dec. 1, 1942, reactions to inaccuracies in this testimony June 11-21, 1943, correspondence from Townsend to Empie Jan.-May 1943 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Congressional Relations- 3 Reports- "Supplementary Statement by Mr. D.S. Myer before the Sub-Committee of the Military Affairs Committee of the U.S. Senate" Jan. 20, 1943, "Minority Report of the Honorable Herman P. Eberharter" Aug. 25, 1943, "Record of the Hearing Held at Colorado River War Relocation Project by Senate Sub-Committee of Military Affairs" Mar. 7, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Outside Employment- WRA project report on Evacuee labor and cotton crop in Parker, Arizona- Nov. 1, 1942, Department of Ag. Report on "Farmer's attitudes toward use of Japanese Evacuees as Farm Labor" Jan. 30, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Outside Employment- statistics on harvest workers, interviews and letters from evacuee workers Sept.-Oct. 1942, Mar.-Apr. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Outside Employment- analysis of questionnaire replies of evacuee harvest workers, analysis of evacuee workers' letters (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Outside Employment- evacuee harvest workers' answers to questionnaires Aug. 11, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Outside Employment- evacuee harvest workers' answers to questionnaires Nov.-Dec. 1942 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings from Los Angeles Times Feb. 1-26, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings from Los Angeles Times Feb. 27-Mar. 24, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings from Los Angeles Times Mar. 25-Spr. 16, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings from Los Angeles Times Apr. 17-July 23, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Outgroup Relations- news clippings from Los Angeles Times Aug. 1-Apr. 14, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Outgroup Relations- newspaper clippings from Poston Press Bulletins about Outgroup relations Sept.-Oct. 1942 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Personality Studies
    - Autobiography - student profiles (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Autobiography - student profiles (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Autobiography - student profiles (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Autobiography - Nisei school teachers (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Autobigraphy - Nisei school teachers (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Autobigrpahy - Psycho-Biological Studies of Personalities - Dr. Leighton, Tom Sasaki (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Autobiography - Autobiography of No. 99 Anonymous (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Personality Studies - Yahiro (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Medical [Restricted] (Box 11, Folder 48)
      Yashida
    - Election - Yamoto (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Administration - Wumion (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Orientation Meeting - Beatty (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Orientation Meeting - Best (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Journal, Block Managers Meeting Minutes, Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Orientation Meeting (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Interview - Crawford (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Administration - Empie (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Administration - Evans (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Administration - Felsted (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Administration - Finley (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Administration - Gelvin (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Administration - Haas (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Personality Studies Staff- Head (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with John Embree, John Collier, and others
    - Personality Studies - Head (actual study) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Staff Meeting topic Press Bulletin (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Hege
    - Personality Studies Staff - James (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Block Managers Meeting -Personalities Studies - Jean (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Administration - Kennedy (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Administration - Personality Studies - Leighton (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Orientation Meeting - Personality Studies - Mahn (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Interview Staff - Mathiesen (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Interview Staff - Miller (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Interview Staff - Nelson (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Interview Staff - Nosoff (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Interview Staff, etc. - Powell (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Minutes - Pressman (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, newspaper - Snelson (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Orientation Meeting - Schnur (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Personnel Issues (Box 12, Folder 16)
      Smith
    - Personnel Issues (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Townsend
    - Administration - Vickers (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Personality Studies - miscellaneous front sheets, priority notes, unindexed biography outline for Tuba City work (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Personality Studies - TAT test notes, reponses (translations) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Personality Studies (Box 12, Folder 21)
      Miaso Furuta - correspondence, autobiography, sentiments (notes)
    - Personality Studies (Box 12, Folder 22)
      Katsumi Takemoto - interview, life story, notes
    - Personality Studies [Restricted (R5)] (Box 12, Folder 23)
      Dave Arata (study by I. Ishino)
    - Army Air Corps Application - George T. Aihara (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Request for assistance - Tsutaye Akamatsu (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Administration - Moto Asakawa (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Personality Studies - George Fujii (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Block Managers Meeting Minutes (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Personal Journal EC - M. Harada (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Notes - Sudo Hashima (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Biographical Statement - Masa Hayashi (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Interview - Changes in Young People over Past Year - Rev. Imai (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Personality Studies - Dr. Tetsuya G. Ishimara - psychological profile (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Personality Studies - miscellaneous notes of I. Ishino (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Personality Studies - Jimmy Ito and Tomo Ito (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Administration - Dr. Kazumi Kasuga, staff (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Personality Studies - Smoot Katow (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Administration - Captain George Kawaichi, staff (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Personality Studies - Mas Kawashima (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Nursery Division and Landscape Division Reports (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Questionnaire - notes (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Pacific Citizen - "Timely Topics" - account of incident, Kido (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - The Family - Rev. Kono (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Interviews - Mich Kunitani (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Administration - Mr. Kurata (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Notes - Personality Studies - Dr. Kushi (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Biographical form - handwritten - Personality Studies - Tatsuo Kushida (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Permanent Self Government - Interview - Frank Kuwahara (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Personality Studies - John Maeno (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Rehearing Request - Mrs. Matsuda (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Personality Studies - Masatani Mitani (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Buddhist Religion in Poston - Henry Miwa (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Personality Studies - Dr. Mizushima (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Personality Studies - Yaetaro Mohri (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Interviews - Personality Studies - Rev. Jitsuo Morikawa (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Writings - Personality Studies- Kenneth Murase (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Personality Studies - Gen. Masayoshi Nagai (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - Personality Studies - Jo Nakai (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Personality Studies - Masatoshi Nakamura (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Personality Studies - R.S. Nishimoto (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - Journal - Leighton - Personality Studies - R.N. Nishimoto (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - Personality Studies - Kay Nishimura (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - Personality Studies - N. Nishino (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - Isamu Noguchi on the Nisei (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - Personality Studies - Seiichi Nomura (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - Personality Studies (Box 12, Folder 66)
      Yoneo Ono
    - Personality Studies - Hidemi Ogawa, Ichino Okada, Rev. Okohiro, Minoru Okamoto, Juro Omori (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - Personality Studies - Fred Ota (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - Personality Studies - Edward Ouchi (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Block Studies - Mr. Ozawa (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Personality Studies - Mrs. Teru Samida (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Administration - Mitsuo Sanbonmatsu (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Personality Studies - Tisasaki's Personal Journal (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - Leighton and James Sora letters (Box 12, Folder 74)
    - Personality Studies - Isamu "Andrew" Sugimoto (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - Personality Studies - Franklyn Sugiyama (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - Personality Studies - S. T. (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - Personal Journal EC - Takemoto (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - Personality Studies - K.U. (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - Personality Studies - Isamu Uchida (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Personality Studies - Kazue Uyeno (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - Tuba City, Leighton, Wakatake letters (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - Personality Studies - Robert Tetsuo Wakatake (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - Personality Studies - Tetsuo Wakatake cont. (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Personality Studies - Tetsuo Wakatake cont. (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Personality Studies - George Akiji Wakatake (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Personality Studies - Jim Yoro Watari (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - Personality Studies - Jim Yoro Watari cont. (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - Recreation - Notes - Personality Studies - personal journals Elizabeth Colson (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Personality Studies - personal journals George Yamaguchi (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Sociological Journal, newspapers
    - Explanation of the Sociological Journal, meeting minutes, reports, newsclippings, notes (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Poston I, July 1942 -, notes, reports, memos, meetings (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Poston I, July 1942 -, official daily information bulletin, clippings (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Poston I, Aug. 1942 -, notes, reports, observations (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Poston I, Aug. 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Poston I, Sept. 1-15, 1942 -, notes, memos (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Poston I, Sept. 1-15, 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Poston I, Sept. 16-30, 1942 -, notes and observations (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Poston I, Oct. 1942, notes, observations (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Poston I, Oct. 1942, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Poston I, Nov. 1942 -, notes, photos, Press Bulletin clippings (photos on paper) (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Poston I, Dec. 1942 -, notes, memos, Christmas programs, meetings, interviews (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Poston I, Jan. 1943, notes (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Poston I, Feb.-Mar. 1943-, photos, notes (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Poston I, II, III- April 1943 -, notes (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Poston I, May-June 1943 -, notes, interview (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Poston II, Aug. 1942 -, notes (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Poston II, Aug. 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Poston II, III- Sept. 1942 -, notes (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Poston II, Sept. 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Poston II, Oct. 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Poston II, Nov.-Dec. 1942 -, notes, clippings, meetings (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Poston III, Aug. 1942 -, notes (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Poston III, Aug. 1942 -, Press clippings (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Poston III, Sept. 1942 -, notes, interviews (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Poston III, Sept. 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Poston III, Oct. 1942 -, notes, conversations (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Poston III, Oct. 1942 -, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Poston III, Nov. 1942 -, notes, Press Bulletin clippings (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Poston III, Dec. 1942 -, notes, observations (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Poston III, Jan.-Feb. 1943 -, notes (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Leighton's notes and observations of administration and internees- June-July (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Leighton's notes and observations of administration and internees- Aug. (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Leighton's notes and observations of administration and internees- Sept. (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Leighton's notes and observations of administration and internees- Oct. (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Leighton's notes and observations of administration and internees- Nov. and Dec. (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Bibliography
    - WRA Bibliography of Japanese in america, Teacher's Bibliography on "Our American Japanese" (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Poston materials
    - Charts, applications, question and answer for evacuees, evacuation notice, poem, report, sketches, invitations, Japanese-American student relocation commencement program (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Poston Chronicle, March - April 1943 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Volume X, no. 24, March 6, 1943 to Vol. XII, no. 8, April 30, 1943
    - Poston Chronicle, January 26 - May 29, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript notes--Leighton, "Governing of Men"
    - Part I- Naval copy-, memos, preface, table of contents, chapter 1 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Part I- Naval copy-, chapter 2-3 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Part I- Naval copy-, chapter 4-6 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Part I- Naval copy-, chapter 7-10 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Part I- Naval copy-, chapter 10-14 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Naval proof:"Governing of Men" (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Part II-, rough draft-purpose, introduction, chapter 1-2 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Part II-, chapters 3-5 and bibliography (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Comments on manuscript, notes (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - Misc. correspondence about the manuscript (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - Manuscript part I (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Manuscript part II (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - Manuscript part III (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - Book Reviews of Manuscript (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous oversized materials
    - WRA Daily News Digest Sept. 1944-Dec. 1945. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Census Studies-, distribution of previous localities (who arrived from where) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Census Studies-, employment/occupation by block (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Census Studies-, distribution of Issei, Nisei, Sansei, Kibei (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Census Studies-, marital status (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Poston Red Cross News (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Teachers- orientation information, bulletins, memos, teacher training information (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - School Newspaper- "Desert Daze" Poston I, May 20-June 17, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - School Newspaper- "Kampus Krier" Poston I, May 7-June 4, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - School Newspaper- "The Petrified News" Poston III, Nov. 16-Dec. 14, 1942 High School (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Bulletins- offers of outside employment June 3-July 8, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Literature, service programs of religious type (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Poston Church Newspapers (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Other Camps- maps, charts on organization, YWCA bulletins, recreation bulletins Mar.-Apr. 1943, proposed Community Advisory Council charter and code of organization, Minodaka irregation in English and Japanese- Mar. 13, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Outside Employment-, charts and maps, placement, wages, attitudes, evacuee harvest workers (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Series II. Manzanar
  - State Department
    - State Department: press releases, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - State Department: publications, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Post War World Council
    - Post War World Council: newsletters (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Records
    - Congressional Records: excerpts from records about Japanese Americans, 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Records, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - Congressional Records, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)